trident.edu 2018-12-30

# Privacy Policy: Trident University

**Trident University (“TUI,” “we” or “us”) respects your concerns about privacy.**

This Privacy Policy applies to www.trident.edu and other online and mobile services that link to or post this Privacy Policy (collectively, the “Online Services”), or through other means in the course of our business relationship with you.

This Privacy Policy describes the types of information we collect, how we may use that information and with whom we may share it. The Privacy Policy also describes the measures we take to protect the security of the personal information. We also tell you how you can reach us to ask us to answer any questions you may have about our privacy practices.

By using the Online Services, you signify your consent to this Privacy Policy. Your use of the Online Services and any information you provide through the Online Services is subject at all times to this Privacy Policy.

**Personal Information We Collect**

When you access or use the Online Services, we may process and collect the following types of information from you:

“Personal Information” is any information that we can reasonably use to identify you. If you are located in the European Economic Area (EEA), Personal Information includes all Personal Data as defined under EEA laws.

“Sensitive Personal Information” includes special categories of Personal Information (e.g., racial or ethnic origin, political opinions, religious or philosophical beliefs, or trade union membership, genetic data, biometric data, data concerning health, and data concerning a natural person’s sex life or sexual orientation) for which applicable law provides enhanced protections.  Sensitive Personal Identifying Information is defined as information that if lost, compromised, or disclosed could result in substantial harm, embarrassment, inconvenience, or unfairness to an individual.

The table below describes the Personal Information and Sensitive Personal Information that we collect, why we collect it, and our legal basis for processing it.

**Purpose** | **Examples** | **Legitimate Interest for Collecting and/or Processing**  
---|---|---  
To process requests to receive information regarding programs and admissions. | Name, email address, phone number, military status, student status, your highest level of education. | The Personal Information collected through the request forms are necessary to contact individuals interested in Trident’s programs and send brochures and other requested information.  
To receive and process scholarship applications. | Name, email address, phone number, military status, student status, your highest level of education. | The Personal Information collected is necessary to facilitate scholarship applications.  
To receive employment applications.  Our site may link to third-party job posting sites which are used to receive and transmit personal information. | Email address, Name, __________, ______________ | The Personal Information collected is necessary to evaluate and process employment applications.  
To join our mailing list | Name, email address | The Personal Information is necessary to facilitate sending you emails from our mailing list.  
To receive and process applications for admission (Trident receives this information through a third-party service provider – currently force.com) | Name, email address, phone number, password and account creation information, address, date of birth, other application information that you voluntarily submit. | The Personal Information collected is necessary to receive and process applications for admissions.  
To facilitate requests to communicate with us via online chat | Name, Email Address, Phone Number, student status | The Personal Information is necessary to facilitate and execute online chat communications.  
  
**Information We Collect**

_Information You Provide Directly to Us_. We and our service providers may collect information that you provide us directly, for example, when you provide us with your contact information. The information that you provide us may include, but is not limited to contact information, such as your name, postal address, email address, telephone number, and fax number.

_Cookies and Information We Collect by Automated Means_. When you use the Online Services, we and our service providers may collect or retain certain information over time and across different websites when you use the Online Services. We and our service providers may collect this information by automated means, using technologies such as cookies, Web server logs and Web beacons.

Cookies are files that websites send to your computer or other Internet-connected device to uniquely identify your browser or to store information or settings in your browser. You can find more information about cookies at [www.allaboutcookies.org](https://www.allaboutcookies.org/) and [www.youronlinechoices.eu](https://www.youronlinechoices.eu/).

Please review your web browser’s preferences to learn how to modify your cookie settings:

Chrome:  <https://support.google.com/chrome/answer/95647>

Firefox:  <https://support.mozilla.org/en-US/kb/cookies-information-websites-store-on-your-computer#w_cookie-settings>

Internet Explorer:  <https://support.microsoft.com/en-us/help/17442/windows-internet-explorer-delete-manage-cookies>

Safari iOS:  <https://support.apple.com/en-us/HT201265>

Safari macOS:  <https://support.apple.com/guide/safari/manage-cookies-and-website-data-sfri11471/mac>

Please note, however, that without cookies, you may not be able to use all of the features of our Online Services. In conjunction with the gathering of information through cookies, our Web servers may log information such as your operating system type, browser type, domain, and other system settings, as well as the language your system uses and the country and time zone where your device is located. The Web server logs also may record information such as the address of the Web page that referred you to the Online Services and the IP address and actual location of the device you use to connect to the Internet. They may also log information about your interaction with the Online Services, such as which pages you visit. Web beacons are snippets of code embedded in webpages and are typically used to monitor activity on a webpage, collect information, or transfer information to servers.

We may use third-party web analytics services on our Online Services, such as those of Google Analytics. These service providers use cookies and web beacons to help us analyze how users use the Online Services. The information collected by the cookies and Web beacons (including your IP address) will be disclosed to these service providers, who use the information to evaluate your use of the Online Services. Google Analytics transmits website use data to Google servers.  Google Analytics does not identify individual users or associate your IP address with any other data held by Google.  We use reports provided by Google Analytics to help us understand website traffic and usage of the Online Services.  To find out more about Google Analytics use of data, please visit “How Google uses data when you use our partners’ sites or apps”, (located at [www.google.com/policies/privacy/partners/](http://www.google.com/policies/privacy/partners/)) for more information. For information about how Google uses the information, see the [Google Privacy Policy](http://www.google.com/policies/privacy/).  To learn about opting out of Google Analytics, you may visit <http://tools.google.com/dlpage/gaoptout>.

We may combine the information you provide us and information we automatically collect with information from public or third-party sources.

**Interest Based Advertising**

The Online Services permits data collection for internet-based advertising.  TUI and third-party vendors, including Google, use cookies to inform, optimize, and serve ads based on past visits to our Online Services.  More specifically, the Online Services have implemented and use display advertising, and we utilize Google Analytics to implement a specific feature called remarketing.  Remarketing is a feature of Google Ads that allows us to optimize the delivery of ad content specifically targeted to a visitor’s interests based upon previous visits to our Online Services.  Please visit <https://support.google.com/analytics/answer/2611268> for more information about remarketing lists in Google Analytics.

If you do not want to use the remarketing feature from Google, you can disable it by changing the appropriate settings at <http://www.google.com/settings/ads>.

There is also a Google Analytics opt-out browser add on that you can download at <https://tools.google.com/dlpage/gaoptout/>.

**Additional Uses of the Information We Collect**

The Online Services permit data collection for internet-based advertising.  We use the information we collect and receive to provide you with products and services and to operate, maintain, and enhance the Online Services. For example:

_To Provide Our Services_. We use the information we collect and receive to provide you with the products, services, or information that you request; to provide you with information about Online Services or required notices; to deliver marketing communications, promotional materials, or advertisements that may be of interest to you; and to customize your experience when using the Online Services, among other things.  Please note that we use third party services providers that provide us advertising services and, as described further herein, we may share the information we collect to any such third-party advertising service provider.

_To Improve Our Services_. We use the information we collect and receive to improve the Online Services we provide, for example by better tailoring content to user needs and preferences, such as by giving you more relevant ads; by generating and analyzing statistics about your use of the Online Services; and by developing new products and services.

_To Communicate With You_. We use the information we collect and receive to communicate with you about our Online Services and products, to respond to you when you contact us, and to let you know about our policies and terms or provide other notices required by law.

_To Maintain and Operate Our Online Services_. We use the information we collect and receive to protect our rights and to detect, prevent, and respond to fraud; intellectual property infringement; violations of industry standards and our policies and terms, such as our Terms of Use; violations of law; or other misuse of the Online Services.

We also may use the information in other ways for which we provide specific notice at the time of collection.

**Sharing of Information**

We may share information we collect or receive in order to provide the products and services that you have requested, when we have your consent, or as otherwise described in this Privacy Policy. We do not rent or sell personal information to third parties.

We may share your information with service providers that perform services on our behalf, such as providing order and payment processing services, processing employment applications, or delivering marketing communications, promotional materials, or advertisements that may be of interest to you. These service providers are not authorized by us to use or disclose the information except as necessary to perform services on our behalf or to comply with legal requirements. We also may share your information among our affiliates. We may share information we collect on the Online Services at your request. For example, if you use the Online Services to send information to a third party, we may identify you as the sender.

We also may disclose information about you to third parties as required by law or regulation and when we have a good faith belief that it is necessary in order to protect the legal rights, safety, and security of TUI, our affiliates, our business partners, users of our Online Services, to respond to and resolve claims or complaints, to prevent fraud or for risk management purposes, and to comply with or respond to law enforcement or legal process or a request for cooperation by a government or other entity.

We reserve the right to transfer information in association with the consideration, negotiation, or completion of a sale or transfer of all or a portion of our business or assets. Should such a sale or transfer occur, we will use reasonable efforts to direct the transferee to use the information you have provided to us in a manner that is consistent with our Privacy Policy.

We may share information that is not reasonably identified with you for any purpose.

The Online Services may contain third party links. This Privacy Policy does not apply to the third-party content; you acknowledge and agree that TUI is not responsible for the collection and use of your information by such third parties that are not under our control. We encourage you to review the privacy policies of those third-party websites or services.

**Do Not Track**

We do not currently support Do Not Track signals but may in the future.  Although we are not a member of the Network Advertising Initiative (NAI) and do not participate in the Digital Advertising Alliance’s (DAA) Self-Regulatory Program, you may wish to investigate these programs, which provide an opt-out feature where consumers can choose not to receive targeted advertising from any NAI or DAA affiliate. These links will take you to the  _[NAI opt out](http://www.networkadvertising.org/managing/opt_out.asp)_  and the  _[DAA opt out](http://www.aboutads.info/choices/)_. If you are located in the European Union, you may prefer to use the  _[EDAA opt out](http://www.youronlinechoices.eu/)_.

**How We Protect Information**

We maintain reasonable administrative, technical and physical safeguards designed to protect the information you provide against accidental, unlawful or unauthorized destruction, loss, alteration, access, disclosure or use. Because no information system can be fully secure, we cannot ensure or warrant the security of any information that you transmit to us and you do so at your own risk.

**How We Retain Information**

We may retain information that can reasonably identify you for as long as we determine is needed for our reasonable business purposes, including to comply with our legal obligations, resolve disputes, and enforce our agreements.

**Facebook Lead Ads**

We occasionally run lead ads on www.facebook.com, and we are committed following Facebook’s Lead Ad Terms <https://www.facebook.com/ads/leadgen/tos>. Should a Facebook user click one of our ads and choose to submit their data to us (this data includes First Name, Last Name, Email, and Phone Number), the user has willingly and expressively given us the right to contact them via phone and/or email, even if they are subscribed on the Do Not Call List. Participation in these Facebook Lead Ads and the forms generated by them are voluntary and you may choose whether or not to disclose information via this format. If a user submits data to you through one of our Facebook Lead Ads, such data will be governed by this Privacy Policy.  Notwithstanding anything to the contrary contained herein, we will not sell Facebook Lead Ad Data under any circumstances.

**International Visitors**

TUI is based in the United States. Regardless of where you use our Online Services or provide information to us, the information may be transferred to and maintained on servers located in the United States, which may not provide the same level of protection for your personal information as your home country and may be available to the United States government or its agencies under a lawful order made in the United States. We may also store your information outside of the United States or transfer it to our affiliates and business partners located in other countries for the purposes described herein. By providing any data through the Online Services, you hereby expressly consent to such transferring and processing of your data in and to the United States and other countries.

**Children’s Information**

The Online Services are not directed to, nor knowingly collect information from, children under the age of 13. If you become aware that your child or any child under your care has provided us with information without your consent, please contact us at the contact information listed below.

**California Privacy Rights**

If you are a resident of California, you may have the right to request and receive information on any third parties to whom TUI has disclosed personal information for marketing purposes within the previous calendar year, along with the type of personal information disclosed. If you would like to make such a request, please contact us at the contact information listed below.

**Links to Other Web Sites**

The Online Services may provide links to other sites for your convenience and information. These websites may be operated by companies other than TUI. Linked websites may have their own privacy policies, which we strongly suggest you review if you visit any linked websites. We are not responsible for the content of any websites that are not operated by us, any use of those websites, or the privacy practices of those websites.

**Updates to Our Privacy Policy**

This Privacy Policy may be updated periodically and without prior notice to you to reflect changes in our information practices or relevant laws. We will post a prominent notice on the Online Services to notify you of any significant changes to our Privacy Policy and indicate at the top of the notice when it was updated. You should review this Policy periodically. Your continued use of the Online Services constitutes your agreement to this Privacy Policy.

**How to Contact Us**

If you have any questions or comments about this Privacy Policy, or if you would like us to update information, we have about you or your preferences, please contact us as indicated below. If you are contacting us by email to request that we change or delete personal information that you submitted through the Online Services, please be sure to tell us which page or form on the Online Services you used to submit your information:

Trident University  
Attention: Office of the Compliance  
5757 Plaza Drive, Suite 100  
Cypress, CA  90630  
_[compliance@trident.edu](mailto:compliance@trident.edu)_
